Nathon Chavez

Austin, Texas Metropolitan Area



nathonchavez01@gmail.com



858-705-9979



linkedin.com/in/nathon-chavez-b8a958211

Summary

Academic and internship experience with SDLC, retail management, budget planning, stakeholder communication, and data analysis. My skills include and focus on full-stack development, including React, React Native, Ruby, Node.js, JS, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap. Lastly, my data analysis skills are curated towards Excel, MySQL, Google Analytics, Git, Linux, Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib), and data visualization(Tableau).

To see my computer science portfolio, please visit the website that I created. https://elated-carson-332cfc.netlify.app/

To view my college transcript:

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-QpTqDC1tstA14YBh56wffXgxvgYU-AE/view?usp=sharing

Experience



Data Analyst

Internal Revenue Service

Aug 2022 - Present (10 months)

Enter, analyze, filter/clean, and visualize taxpayer data through programs such as Excel, SCRIPPS, and ISRP - meeting and often exceeding daily and weekly output quotas.



Prep Cook

Dominic's Italian Gourmet

Jul 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years)

Prepare and maintain ingredients for the chefs, such as cutting vegetables, making dough, preparing the broth, and making marinara. Often satisfied and exceeded management and customer expectations during the heavy workflow, busy days, and moments of adversity.



Store Associate

Defense Commissary Agency

Mar 2022 - Jun 2022 (4 months)

Stocked and maintained store merchandise. With help of other team members, MCAS lwakuni was the highest-grossing Commissary in Japan because of our efficiency of workflow & customer satisfaction.

Employment was short because I PCS'ed from Japan to Austin.



Data Analyst Intern

Enterprise Hall

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 (2 months)

Analyze and describe data sent in weekly via Excel; create algorithms that display the specified/desired data through Python. When finished, we needed to send in the programs and an in-depth analysis of what we did to solve the problem.

Web Development Intern

National STEM Honor Society (NSTEM)

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021 (3 months)

Developing and debugging the organization's website with HTML, CSS, JS, and WordPress. Additionally, I analyzed website data which includes traffic and communications between various organizations.

Vendor

Top Gun Services LLC

Jan 2021 - Mar 2022 (1 year 3 months)

Stock and maintain accounts varied in food and items, some of which includes Frito Lays, Banquet, and Birds Eye

Social Media Manager

Iwakuni Thrift Store

Sep 2019 - Mar 2021 (1 year 7 months)

Upkeeping the social media page of the thrift store included: updating what was in stock with Excel, analyzing and reporting data inquiries on sales, posting, replying to messages, and updating the store page.

On occasion, I submitted and processed payroll when management was not available.

Education



Nucamp Coding Bootcamp

Computer Science - Full Stack Web and Mobile Development

2022 - 2022

A full-stack development boot camp taught us to utilize libraries and platforms such as Bootstrap, React, React Native, database management, and the backend with MongoDB, Express, and Node.js.

Altcademy

Computer Science - Full Stack Development

2021 - 2022

A full-stack development boot camp where we learned HTML, CSS & JS, Dynamic Website Development through Ajax, jQuery and DOM Manipulation, ReactJS with ES6, and Ruby On Rails. At the end, built a full-stack web application that utilized AWS for the backend and used several libraries for the front-end.

Southern New Hampshire University

Bachelor's degree (In Progress), Computer Science

2019 - 2023

Final year into my bachelor's degree, will be graduating soon.

Licenses & Certifications

G Advanced Google Analytics - Google

Issued Oct 2021 - Expires Oct 2024

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Java • Data Analysis • C++ • JavaScript • Google Analytics • Full-Stack Development • Mobile Application Development • Microsoft Office • Microsoft Excel

Honors & Awards



Department of Defense Cyber Awareness Training - United States Department of Defense

Apr 2022

This course provides an overview of current cybersecurity threats and best practices to keep information and information systems secure at home and at work. The training also reinforces best practices to protect classified, controlled unclassified information (CUI), and personally identifiable information (PII).

Academic Excellence - The National Society of Leadership and Success Sep 2019

Meeting or exceeding a GPA higher than 3.5



High Honors - Summa Cum Laude - Southern New Hampshire University

May 2021

Have a GPA higher than 3.85 for a certain amount of semesters.